In jiu-jitsu,
it takes about 10 years to get a black
belt.
There are some outliers,
but I think BJ Penn has got the record for
getting it in
three and a half years.
So even the most incredible
journey to black belt still took three
and a half years, and often those people
just take 10 years of learning
and condense it down.
Now, white belts are the spazziest.
They're the most dangerous.
Sounds crazy. When you go to train,
you might think the black belts
are dangerous.
They say that a black belt with bad
intentions is less dangerous than a white
belt
with good intentions.
White belts hurt each other because they
don't know what
they're doing. But the beautiful thing
is everyone in jiu-jitsu as a white belt
is shit. They are awful.
But there's a magical thing about them
that when they
train, they know they're shit
and they just enjoy it.
They get shit on by everyone else because
everyone they go up against knows exactly
what they're going to do,
and every single person knows every single
submission and
trick that they have.
Yet they enjoy it and they turn up,
and it's almost still a
brilliant first two years. Then
when you get your blue belt, you
are finally now a
colored belt,
but still the majority of people
are going to shit on you, but they
still appreciate it. For some reason,
maybe in the modern world we live in,
we seem
to think that we can get very good at
acquiring skills in weeks and months.
If you go into any jiu-jitsu gym and say,
"I want to be a black belt within a
year," it is physically impossible.
So when we look at content,
email marketing, sales copy, landing
pages, VSLs, all the things
that we've spoken about,
we need to look at the journey
in years. And I know that's not sexy.
I wish I did have a certain system
that could do it for you in a couple of
months,
but it's just not the way it works.
Now looking back, I'm a brown belt now.
It's purple, blue.
Every time I look back at any competition
footage, I am
embarrassed and I am like, "Oh my God,
look at this cringe-worthy
idiot here." But at the time,
I thought I was killing it.
And anytime I look back,
the one thing I love is when I
was a white belt, I was
just as happy as I was at blue belt,
and I was just as happy as I was at purple
belt. The levels changed,
but the enjoyment doesn't.
And I think it's just really important for
us to look at the journey of where we
are and appreciate that some of us
are white belts in things,
and that's okay.
But the only way to get better
is to show up, to turn
up, and occasionally get your ass kicked.
There is no way around it.
You cannot get better at jiu-jitsu just
sitting at home. You can't.
The majority of people quit at white belt.